<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud Architecture and Design on OpenNebula</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud Architecture and Design on OpenNebula</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Architecture Design</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/cloud_architecture_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/cloud_architecture_design/</guid>
      <description>This page describes the high-level steps to design and deploy an OpenNebula cloud.&#xA;To familiarize yourself with deployment and daily operations, or if you want to quickly try an Edge, Hybrid or Multi-cloud deployment, we strongly recommend you begin with the Quick Start Guide. In the Quick Start, you can:&#xA;Install an OpenNebula Front-end Deploy on-demand Edge Clusters on remote cloud providers Deploy Virtual Machines and Kubernetes clusters As you follow the tutorials you will learn the basic usage and operation of your cloud.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Edge Cloud Reference Architecture</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/edge_cloud_reference_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/edge_cloud_reference_architecture/</guid>
      <description>To support digital transformation initiatives, IT departments need the right blend of on-premises, public and edge cloud environments to support a variety of existing and emerging use cases while avoiding vendor lock-in and enabling cost optimization. They also need to combine virtual machine workloads with containerized applications from Kubernetes in a shared environment to get the best of both worlds: mature virtualization technologies and orchestration of application containers.&#xA;This document presents a powerful distributed Edge Cloud Architecture for OpenNebula composed of Edge Clusters that can run any workload - both virtual machines and containerized applications — on any resource — bare metal or virtualized — anywhere on premises and on a cloud provider.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Cloud Reference Architecture</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/open_cloud_reference_architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/understand_opennebula/cloud_architecture_and_design/open_cloud_reference_architecture/</guid>
      <description>The OpenNebula Cloud Reference Architecture is a blueprint to guide IT architects, consultants, cloud‬ ‭administrators, and field practitioners in the design and deployment of private, hybrid, and edge clouds‬ ‭fully based on ‬‭open source platforms and technologies‭. ‬‭It is based on the collective information and‬ ‭experiences of hundreds of users and client engagements. Besides the main logical components and‬ ‭interrelationships within the architecture, this document includes references to software products, specific‬ ‭configurations, and requirements of infrastructure platforms recommended for a‬‭ smooth OpenNebula‬ ‭installation‭.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
