<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketplace Appliances on OpenNebula</title>
    <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketplace Appliances on OpenNebula</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/overview/</guid>
      <description>The public OpenNebula Marketplace includes easy-to-use appliances, which are preconfigured Virtual Machines that can be used to deploy different services. These appliance include the images with all necessary packages installed for the service run, including the OpenNebula contextualization packages and specific scripts that bring the service up on boot. This allows to customize the final service state by the cloud user via special contextualization parameters.&#xA;No security credentials are persisted in the distributed appliances.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing Marketplace Appliances</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/marketapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/marketapps/</guid>
      <description>A Marketplace Appliance is a generic resource (an entry on the marketplaceapp pool) that can be of any of the following three different types:&#xA;Image, a single Image, optionally including a VM template. VM, a VM template referring to one or more images. Service, a multi-VM service composed of one or more templates associated with images. This guide introduces the process to create and manage Marketplace Appliances.&#xA;Exploring Marketplace Appliances You can list the Marketplace Appliances (apps) with onemartketapp list command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OneKE Service (K8s)</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/oneke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/oneke/</guid>
      <description>OneKE is a minimal hyperconverged Kubernetes platform that comes with OpenNebula out of the box. OneKE is based on RKE2 - Rancher’s Next Generation Kubernetes Distribution with preinstalled components to handle:&#xA;storage persistence, ingress traffic, load balancing. The full documentation of the OneKE appliance is maintained in the OpenNebula Apps project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/wordpress/</guid>
      <description>This OpenNebula marketplace appliance comes with a preinstalled WordPress service and includes the following features:&#xA;Based on the latest AlmaLinux 8 Linux distribution (for x86-64). No default login (local or SSH) password - must be provided via contextualization The full documentation of the WordPress appliance is maintained in the OpenNebula Apps project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VNF and Virtual Router</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/vnf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/vnf/</guid>
      <description>The VR in OpenNebula is a solution to common problems regarding management of VNETs and routing, including:&#xA;Keepalive Failover, High-Availability for the Service Virtual Router itself. Router4, to fine control routing between your virtual networks. NAT4, so you can enable your private virtual networks to reach the Internet. HAProxy Load Balancer, a robust layer4 (TCP) reverse-proxy/load-balancing solution. Keepalive LVS Load Balancer, so called layer4 switching, a high-performance load-balancing solution. SDNAT4, a public to private, private to public IP address mapping (SNAT + DNAT).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>minIO</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/minio_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/apps-marketplace/marketplace_appliances/minio_intro/</guid>
      <description>Placeholder text for new page based on the minIO wiki, https://github.com/OpenNebula/one-apps/wiki/minio_intro.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
