<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automatic Deployment of OpenNebula with OneDeploy on OpenNebula</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automatic Deployment of OpenNebula with OneDeploy on OpenNebula</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/one_deploy_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/one_deploy_overview/</guid>
      <description>OpenNebula provides OneDeploy, a set of Ansible playbooks that allows you to automatically deploy an OpenNebula cloud in a simple and convenient way.&#xA;Ansible is a Python application for IT automation. It can deploy software, configure systems, and orchestrate complex deployments and workflows.&#xA;The Ansible playbooks in OneDeploy install a complete OpenNebula cloud, including the Front-end with the OneFlow and OneGate services, and the Sunstone UI. Before running the playbooks, you can modify variables to configure the OpenNebula cloud that will be created.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Deployment - Local Storage</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/one_deploy_tutorial_local_ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/one_deploy_tutorial_local_ds/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this tutorial, we’ll use OneDeploy to automatically deploy a simple OpenNebula cloud, with one Front-end and two Hosts using local storage. In this configuration the virtual disk images are transferred from the Front-end to the Hypervisors’ local storage using the SSH protocol.&#xA;This sample architecture uses a basic network configuration, a flat (bridged) network, where each VM’s IP is part of the same network as the Hypervisors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Deployment - Shared Storage</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/one_deploy_tutorial_shared_ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/cloud_installation/automatic_deployment_of_opennebula_with_one_deploy/one_deploy_tutorial_shared_ds/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this tutorial, we’ll use OneDeploy to automatically deploy a simple OpenNebula cloud, with one Front-end and two Hosts using storage shared over NFS. In this configuration, the OpenNebula Front-end and Hypervisor nodes read datastore images from an NFS share available on the network.&#xA;This sample architecture uses a basic network configuration, a flat (bridged) network, where each VM’s IPs is part of the same network as the Hypervisors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
