<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on OpenNebula</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on OpenNebula</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/docs/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/overview/</guid>
      <description>&#xA;OpenNebula includes a number of extensions and plug-ins that allows the integration of OpenNebula with other open source software. In this guide we review the integration of OpenNebula with following third party tools:&#xA;Ansible: to manage common OpenNebula resources, e.g. VMs, images or hosts, using Ansible playbooks Terraform: to create and manage OpenNebula clusters resources (e.g VMs, images, services, …) using the OpenNebula Terraform Provider </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/terraform/</guid>
      <description>Terraform is used to create, manage, and manipulate infrastructure resources (e.g. physical machines, VMs, network switches, containers, etc.). Almost any infrastructure noun can be represented as a resource in Terraform. The OpenNebula provider is officially supported by HashiCorp and fully open source, the repository is available here.&#xA;The OpenNebula provider is used to interact with OpenNebula resources through Terraform. The provider allows you to manage your OpenNebula clusters resources. It needs to be configured with proper credentials before it can be used.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ansible</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/ansible/</guid>
      <description>OpenNebula Ansible modules allow managing common OpenNebula resources, e.g. VMs, images or hosts, using Ansible playbooks. In the latest Ansible version OpenNebula modules are part of the collection community.general. Formerly, they were distributed together with Ansible main package.&#xA;For the module usage, please follow the official Ansible documentation:&#xA;one_host.py one_image.py one_service.py one_vm.py one_template.py Dependencies For OpenNebula Ansible modules Python bindings PYONE are necessary, for one_image.py also legacy Python OCA</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OneSwap</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/oneswap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/tools/oneswap/</guid>
      <description>Placeholder text for page that needs to be written, probably linking to the GitHub repo or the wiki.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
