<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configuration Management EE on OpenNebula</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configuration Management EE on OpenNebula</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/overview/</guid>
      <description>Important Complete feature is available in OpenNebula Enterprise Edition. Only a single functionality comes in Community Edition.&#xA;OpenNebula has tens of configuration files, where cloud administrators can fine-tune the behavior of their cloud environment. When doing an upgrade to a newer minor OpenNebula version (X.Y), unfortunately, all custom changes in configuration files must be migrated to new configuration files. OpenNebula Enterprise Edition comes with a dedicated tool (onecfg), which automates and simplifies the upgrade of configuration files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic Usage</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/usage/</guid>
      <description>This section covers onecfg tool subcommands:&#xA;status - Versions status init - Initialize version management state validate - Validate current configuration files diff - Identify changes in configuration files patch - Apply ad-hoc changes (from diff) in configuration files upgrade - Upgrade configuration files to a new version Important This command must be always run under privileged user root directly or via sudo. For example:&#xA;$ sudo onecfg status The tool comes with help for each subcommand and command-line option.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diff Formats</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/diff_formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/diff_formats/</guid>
      <description>The configuration management tool onecfg allows us to compare the configuration files to identify user changes against the OpenNebula distributed files. The result of a comparison, the differential output, describes all the individual changes which were made and which can even be applied again later or on a different machine.&#xA;The following table shows supported formats by each subcommand:&#xA;Format Description onecfg diff onecfg patch text Easy human-readable text YES (default) NO line Single line for one change YES YES (default) yaml Complete change structure YES YES Only line format will be described in a detail, as it’s powerful in achieving even complex changes and easy enough to read or write manually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/conflicts/</guid>
      <description>The configuration files upgrade is a complex process, during which many problems may arise. The root cause of all problems are the users’ customizations made in the configuration files in places that also change in a newer version. Because the upgrade process tries to apply changes from newer versions to existing files, the tool can be confused when it reaches the incompatibly modified part.&#xA;In case of a problem, the upgrade process terminates and leaves the state of configuration files unchanged.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appendix - List of Configurations</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/docs/releases/release_information/configuration_management_ee/appendix/</guid>
      <description>The following table describes all configuration files and their type from directories&#xA;/etc/one/ /var/lib/one/remotes/ managed by the onecfg tool:&#xA;Name Type /etc/one/alertmanager/alertmanager.yml YAML /etc/one/auth/ldap_auth.conf YAML w/ ordered arrays /etc/one/auth/server_x509_auth.conf YAML /etc/one/auth/x509_auth.conf YAML /etc/one/az_driver.conf YAML /etc/one/az_driver.default Plain file (or XML) /etc/one/cli/*.yaml YAML w/ ordered arrays /etc/one/defaultrc Shell /etc/one/ec2_driver.conf YAML /etc/one/ec2_driver.default Plain file (or XML) /etc/one/ec2query_templates/*.erb Plain file (or XML) /etc/one/hm/hmrc Shell /etc/one/econe.conf YAML /etc/one/fireedge-server.conf YAML /etc/one/fireedge/provision/providers.d-extra/*.yaml YAML /etc/one/fireedge/provision/providers.d/*.yaml YAML /etc/one/fireedge/provision/provision-server.conf YAML /etc/one/fireedge/sunstone/*/*.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
