<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hci Cluster Provisions on OpenNebula</title>
    <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hci Cluster Provisions on OpenNebula</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/overview/</guid>
      <description>HCI Clusters features an hyperconvergent storage configuration based on Ceph. Compared to the Edge Cluster, HCI provides a high available solution. The HCI Clusters are based on bare-metal servers and support the LXC and KVM hypervisors.&#xA;How Should I Read This Chapter In this chapter you can find a guide on how to automatically deploy HCI Clusters on bare-metal on:&#xA;Amazon AWS Edge Clusters On-Premise Edge Cluster Hypervisor Compatibility HCI Clusters are compatible with the KVM and LXC hypervisors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS HCI Cluster</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/aws_cluster_ceph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/aws_cluster_ceph/</guid>
      <description>AWS HCI Cluster Implementation HCI Cluster Nodes The HCI cluster consists of three different type of servers:&#xA;Full nodes, run Ceph OSD and Monitor daemons as well as the selected hypervisor. In order to get a fault tolerant cluster a number of 3 nodes of this type is recommended. OSD nodes, run Ceph OSD daemon and the selected hypervisor. Hypervisor-only nodes, run the selected hypervisor and the Ceph client tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-Premise HCI Cluster</title>
      <link>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/onprem_cluster_ceph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opennebula.github.io/website/docs/hybrid_multi_cloud/automated_hybrid_cluster_provisioning/hci_cluster_provisions/onprem_cluster_ceph/</guid>
      <description>On-Premises HCI Implementation An On-Premises Edge Cluster with Ceph consists of a set of hosts with the following requirements:&#xA;Host Subsystem Configuration &amp;amp; Requirements Operating System Ubuntu 20.04 Focal installation. SSH is configured in the host to grant root passwordless access with the oneadmin credentials. Networking Configured management interface. The OpenNebula front-end can reach the hosts through this network. Separated interface connected to the Internet. VMs will access the Internet through this network.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
